FIND YOUR S.Q.! What is your Suspense Quotient? How Much Suspense Can You Take?
The Last Voyage is a thriller, drama, action film directed by Andrew L. Stone.
Claridon is scheduled for her five last voyages
after thirty-eight years of service.
After an explosion in the boiler room, Captain Robert
Adams is reluctant to evacuate the steamship.
While the crew fights to hold a bulkhead between the flooded boiler room and the engine room and avoid the sinking of the vessel, the passenger Cliff Henderson struggles
against time trying to save his beloved wife Laurie Henderson, who is trapped under a steel beam in her cabin, with the support of the crew member Hank Lawson.
Cliff Henderson, played by Robert Stack.
Laurie Henderson, played by Dorothy Malone.
Capitaine Robert Adams, played by George Sanders.
Second Engineer Walsh, played by Edmond O'Brien.
Hank Lawson, played by Woody Strode.
Chief Engineer Pringle, played by Jack Kruschen.
The Last Voyage is a 1960 Metrocolor American disaster film starring Robert
Stack, Dorothy Malone, George Sanders, and Edmond O'Brien.
It was written and directed by Andrew L.
The film centers on the sinking of an aged ocean liner in the
Pacific Ocean following an explosion in its boiler room.
The ship used in the film was the condemned French luxury liner SS Ile de France, which played a major role
in rescue operations during the 1956 Andrea Doria disaster, off Nantucket, Massachusetts.
The film explores themes of explosion, trapped, boiler room.
The tone is emotional and intense.